Andrea McKenzie

mckenzie.andrea.m@gmail.com

917 674 6154

https://github.com/SiouxsieAsylum

Full-stack developer who's always in beta. Proficient in developing Express.js applications with highly structured PostGresSql databases that either stand alone or exist as an API that feeds data to a React.js client-side application. Before embarking on mu journey as a developer, I was a retail beer buyer for Whole Foods Market with 6+ years of customer relations, 3 years of purchasing experience and 2 years of supervisory experience.

Projects:

Express, React, PSQL

Reci-Pea 2.0 Recipe-to-shopping-list application that takes ingredients and adds them to a user's shopping list. Served as database architect and back-end point.

https://git.generalassemb.ly/s jciasullo/project3-recipeshopper

Express, PSQL, EJS

DateTime

User authenticated event-posting and sharing application. Soon to feature email and push notifications.

https://github.com/SiouxsieA sylum/datetime

React, External API

Wine-By-Dre

Mock online wine store fed with an external Heroku API. Soon to feature local storage for a mock

https://github.com/SiouxsieA sylum/Wine-By-Dre

Experience:

General Assembly, New York, NY

Full-Stack Developer

Developed and maintained various full-stack applications with Node.js, Express.Js, Postgresql, React.js, and Ruby on Rails that integrate eternal APIs and are styled with expertly crafted CSS and Javascript.

Perscholas: Bronx, NY

Front-End Web Developer

August 2017 - October 2017

Developed and maintained static websites with varying levels of interactivity, size, and complexity. Cultivated an eye for UX/UI design. Mastered the new features of HTML5 and CSS3.

Whole Foods Market: Various Locations

Specialty Beer Buyer/Equipment Purchaser

Sept 2013 - August 2017

Directly coordinated orders with distributors to maximize accuracy and negotiate prices to maximize profit margin. Streamlined interdepartmental and vertical communication. Worked directly with store and regional leadership to troubleshoot, fix and clean broken growler lines.

AGRION Inc.: Remote

Market Report Writer Feb 2014-Sept 2014

Performed market research and wrote analytical, concise snapshots of marketing reports on cutting-edge clean energy, clean tech, and sustainability issues, including weekly roundtable discussions. Reports cover a wide range of topics including renewable energy, green buildings, green data centers, energy storage, and corporate sustainability.

Proficiencies:

- **Group Git**
- PSOL/SOL
- Node.is
- Express.js
- Javascript
- Java
- CSS3 animations and transitions
- 6+ years in customer relations
- 3+ years vendor relations

Education:

General Assembly: 2017 Web Development Immersive

PerScholas: 2017 #Codebridge

Self-Taught

2yrs

Hunter College: 2013

B.A. in English Cum Laude